<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jorge López</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jorge López</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting public holidays by country</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-public-holidays-by-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-public-holidays-by-country/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been recently working on a time series model to which I wanted to include the public holidays of Spain and Portugal. After trying different approaches I decided to move forward with prophet which, by the way, I strongly recommend it.
But this post comes to my mind because I’d like to tell some options we have to get the public holidays by country. I don’t want to go into details about the specificities of what a public holidays mean (regional or local ones are excluded in this analysis, for example).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making my own website with blogdown</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-02-01-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-02-01-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>The first thing I’d recommend to anyone who wants to build a website from R using blogdown is to read the book of the author of this package, Yihui Xie.
Therefore, this post isn’t intended to be a guide on how to make your own website but a way to tell my experience through the process. The details of what each folder should contain within the project are fully and very well explained on the book linked above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encuentro de usuarios R en Canarias</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-01-31-encuentro-usuarios-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-01-31-encuentro-usuarios-r/</guid>
      <description>Nada me complace más que iniciar esta nueva web y blog anunciando que el próximo 25 de marzo se llevará a cabo la primera reunión de usuarios de R –#rstats– en Canarias.
El encuentro se realizará en la Sociedad de Promoción Económica de Gran Canaria durante todo el día y estará organizado por el también reciente grupo de usuarios de R en Canarias.
La inscripción y propuesta de charlas (!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>