<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jorge López</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jorge López</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Encuentro de usuarios R en Canarias</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-01-31-encuentro-usuarios-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-01-31-encuentro-usuarios-r/</guid>
      <description>Nada me complace más que iniciar esta nueva web y blog anunciando que el próximo 25 de marzo se llevará a cabo la primera reunión de usuarios de R –#rstats– en Canarias.
El encuentro se realizará en la Sociedad de Promoción Económica de Gran Canaria durante todo el día y estará organizado por el también reciente grupo de usuarios de R en Canarias.
La inscripción y propuesta de charlas (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encuentro de usuarios R en Canarias</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-02-01-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-02-01-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>The first thing I’d recommend to anyone who wants to build a website from R using blogdown is to read the book of the author of this package, Yihui Xie.
Therefore, this post isn’t intended to be a guide on how to make your own website but a way to tell my experience through the process. The details of what each folder should contain within the project are fully and very well explained on the book linked above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me / Sobre mí</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Born and raised in Gran Canaria, the Canary Islands, in northwest Africa.
I graduated in Economics at University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria with a MSc in Statistics at Polytechnic University of Catalonia in the lovely Barcelona (2017). On the professional side, I am currently working as a Data Scientist at Kernel Analytics.
I am a R enthusiast as well as interested in Statistics, Economics, Politics and… a devoted supporter of my football team, UD Las Palmas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to contact me through my email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Nothing to see here&amp;hellip; Move along!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>